plagiarismdetect.com 2011-12-31

# Privacy Policy - PlagiarismDetect.com

As a part of its services of PlagiarismDetect.com, must collect and store specific, private information from its users. As such, PlagiarismDetect.com adheres to the privacy principles enforced at PlagiarismDetect.com. Your privacy is important to us. To better protect your privacy we provide this Privacy Statement explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your personal information is collected and used. This Privacy Statement applies to all personally identifiable information collected or submitted on the PlagiarismDetect.com web site (the "Site"). To make this Privacy Statement easy to find, we make it available on our homepage and at every point where personally identifiable information may be requested. Although this Site provides links to third-party web sites, they are not covered by this Privacy Statement. PlagiarismDetect.com assumes no responsibility for the privacy or security of information you provide to any third party through linked web sites or any other means. By using this Site, you agree that you have reviewed and understood our Terms of Use and this Privacy Statement to your full satisfaction, that you accept and are subject to our Usage Policy and this Privacy Statement, and that PlagiarismDetect.com is permitted to use your personal information as set forth below.

## 1\. Personal Information

**Registration**

Personal information is requested for registration to our service for the following purposes: 1. To verify the identity of a registrant in relation to their authority to register a specific academic institution. 2. To obtain the most complete contact information for administration of the registrant's account. 3. To inform the registrant of changes in PlagiarismDetect.com functionality, PlagiarismDetect.com auxiliary services, and PlagiarismDetect.com promotions.

**Trial**

Personal information is requested for trial use of our service for the following purposes: 1. To inform the trial user of changes in PlagiarismDetect.com functionality, PlagiarismDetect.com auxiliary services, and PlagiarismDetect.com promotions. 2. To request trial user's evaluation and recommendations for the PlagiarismDetect.com service.

**Paper Submission**

Personal information is requested for access to our paper submission web pages for the following purposes: 1. To identify the individual connected to any uploaded manuscript. 2. To provide receipt and confirmation of successful text uploads. The type of information we request is connected to the above-noted purposes. For example, we collect contact information such as name, IP address, and email address for a registered user in order to facilitate use of the PlagiarismDetect.com service and facilitate customer relations. In addition to the specific uses noted above, PlagiarismDetect.com also uses your personal information to process your requests and transactions, offer or furnish additional products and services, personalize the types of information you receive from PlagiarismDetect.com, assess trends in the use of our Site or purchases of products or services, facilitate market research and statistical studies, develop content and functionality that helps us serve our customers' needs, and improve the service and products we provide. PlagiarismDetect.com may also use your personal information to prevent harm or injury, to prevent fraud, to protect our legal interests, to comply with or respond to legal process, and to comply with applicable laws. Access to your personal information by 3rd parties will only occur with the signed confirmation from the registered user, as stated in the agreement on the registration page. This approval includes, but is not limited to, one registered user allowing PlagiarismDetect.com to provide his or her contact information to another registered user for document source analysis tracking. For example, if material uploaded to our database matches material from a later upload, contact information related to the former is given to the latter upload's registered user for follow-up. As we continue to develop our business, we might sell or buy businesses or assets, or PlagiarismDetect.com might be acquired by another company. In any of those circumstances, personal information in our databases may be included among the transferred assets.

## 2\. Cookies

When you visit the Site, we may place a "cookie," a small computer file containing information about the user, on your computer to help us recognize and serve you better when you return. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to personally identifiable information while on our Site. Once you close your browser, the cookie simply terminates. For instance, by setting a cookie on our Site, you would not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while on our Site. If you reject the cookie, you may still use our Site. The only drawback to this is that you will be limited in some areas of our Site. Cookies also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our Site. Some of our business partners use cookies on our Site (e.g., advertisers). However, we have no access to or control over these cookies.

## 3\. Choice

When you provide personally identifiable information to us, you will be able to choose whether we may disclose such information in a personally identifiable form to a third party or whether the information may be used in personally identifiable form for purposes different from the purposes for which it was originally collected or that you have subsequently authorized. You will have the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us when we first request your personal information. You can also opt out of receiving further communications from us by sending an e-mail to  You can request removal of your personally identifiable information from our databases by contacting us as noted in Section 12 (Notices) below. To honor your request, we will need the exact information you want removed, and information sufficient for us to identify the type of communication you received from us.

## 4\. Transfer to Unrelated Third Parties

If we transfer personally identifiable information to a third party that is acting as our agent, we will require that the third party agree to confidentiality requirements.

## 5\. Security

We have physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect personal information we collect online, including the use of passwords to gain access to your personal information. To protect your privacy and security, you must keep your password confidential. However, even with such measures, no one is able to guarantee that unauthorized third parties will not be able to bypass these measures or otherwise capture information you provide over the internet.

## 6\. Data Integrity

We will take reasonable steps to see that the personal information in our systems is relevant for its intended use, accurate, complete, and current.

## 7\. Enforcement

PlagiarismDetect.com will conduct periodic reviews of compliance to verify that this Privacy Statement is accurate, comprehensive, prominently displayed, complete, implemented, and accessible. Any employee who violates this Privacy Statement may be subject to disciplinary action. If you feel that PlagiarismDetect.com is not abiding by this Privacy Statement, you should contact PlagiarismDetect.com as noted in Section 12 (Notices) below.

## 8\. Special Rules Applicable to Data Collected or Processed in the European Union

This Privacy Statement applies to all personally identifiable data that is subject to the European Union's Data Protection Directive and that is transferred to the United States, even if not collected at this Site. PlagiarismDetect.com has enrolled in the Safe Harbor System established by the U.S. Department of Commerce to meet the requirements of the European Commission's Directive on Data Protection. Onward transfers will be permitted only to other persons or entities who have agreed to provide a continuing adequate level of protection through participation in the Safe Harbor program or one of the other means permitted under EU Directive 95/46 EC and implementing Member State laws. If you have any concern or complaint regarding PlagiarismDetect.com compliance with the Safe Harbor Principles - please contact PlagiarismDetect.com as noted in Section 12 (Notices) below. PlagiarismDetect.com will investigate your concern or complaint and will attempt to resolve the matter with you.

## 9\. Changes to this Policy

We reserve the right to make changes to this Privacy Statement at any time. Please check the Privacy Statement when you use the Site to ensure that you are aware of any changes in our privacy practices. Our Privacy Statement will indicate the date it was last updated. If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify you via e-mail at the last email address you have provided to us. You will have a choice as to whether or not we use your information in this different manner. If you elect not to allow us to use your information in this different manner, we will continue to use such information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected.

## 10\. Notices

Please direct all inquiries regarding the Privacy Statement as follows: 1. Contact us by email at . 2. In the subject line, type "PlagiarismDetect.com Privacy Policy." 3. Specify the exact nature of your inquiry. 4. Provide us with all necessary contact information for follow-up response.
